[Music]
foreign
this is Ravi welcome back to Tasca
automation tutorial
so this is our lesson five
where I'm gonna teach you what is model
based test automation
and why does Tasker tries and testoster
follows model based test automation
and then I'm going to show you some
standard modules of Tosca that comes
along with your
Tasker installation
I I think I already published four
YouTube videos I highly recommend you
guys to go through those videos before
you watch this session
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
okay
so model based test automation
is being used by trisantis Tasker
why
because the model based test automation
advantages are
very good compared to script based
automation
the model contains so the model whatever
Tasker is using right those models
contains the technical information and
the expected behavior of your system
under test
so the model is then so if you see on
the screen right
in the middle there is a model right
which is called module in the form of a
tasker so you're gonna get familiar from
the next session onwards why do we use
models and then how to create test cases
for now just listen as a theoretical
part okay so from next session onwards
we are going to interact with all these
modules models and then test cases okay
so the model whatever is created is
being then fed with business data needed
for testing with in the form of for
testing which in the form of test cases
so basically the model whatever is
created is then fed with business data
needed for testing which forms your test
cases so basically the model or the
modules itself forms test cases once you
feed the business data very simple and
you need not to have any scripting
knowledge anyone can contribute to
automation because of this model based
test automation
and also it reduces the maintenance if
your application system under test has
been changed for example then you just
need to update the model
which is called module
and then those changes will
automatically be made to all impacted
test cases you need not to change the
test Case by test case okay that's the
very Advantage okay and these models can
be reused as many times as you need
these models can be reused as many times
as possible and as many test cases as
possible okay so that's the advantage
okay and then
the next agent item is standard modules
in task
the standard module
is actually comes along with the Tasker
installation
okay so what is the advantage of this
standard module so this stores very
basic elements and functions that are
useful
for any kind of application automation
so these are reusable modules that you
need need not to build as they are
already available for you because for
example you need to interact with an
Excel sheet
you need to open an Excel sheet right
you want to handle pop-up boxes so all
these reusable I mean to basically
interact or to do all these actions you
have to build some scripts right
reusable functions so in this case you
need not to build them these are already
available as a module standard modules
right open URL this is also one reusable
function so that is available as a
standard module okay so all these are
all actually reusable modules that you
need not to build and you need not to
spend time because these are readily
available in task
and how and where you can find these
Tasker standard modules so let me let's
jump onto the system and see what are
these standards modules how can we use
them and where can you find in the task
okay so let's jump onto the system
to all viewers uh a big thank you
whoever watching my YouTube videos
so what I can observe uh around 86.8
percent of the viewers are watching my
videos but uh they have not subscribed
to my channel
I would recommend and I would request
everyone please do subscribe to the
channel
and encourage me in posting more and
more videos uh which are helpful for you
guys
thank you
okay so where can we find uh
Tasker standard modules okay so this is
my uh task 16 okay
so when you are creating a new workspace
right click on create new workspace I've
already explained you how to create
workspace in my previous sessions okay
so when you are creating a new workspace
you can see here when I'm clicking on
use workspace template right this is
where the standard dot TSU file is
available standard modules okay let's
copy this path and let me go to that
path okay
so this is your
path where I have installed my
Tasker when I am installing my Tasker it
creates all these folders in this path
okay so under this I can see there is a
file called standard.tsu
this is what the Tasker standard module
okay so if I use this task as standard
module let's create one workspace
standard module
understand it okay
let's create this workspace I'm using
the standard module that is provided by
Tasker Okay click on OK so where can I
see the modules okay so once it creates
the workspace I'm gonna navigate to
modules and then I'm gonna show you what
are these standard modules
okay what are all the different standard
modules that are available
in
Tasker
okay so if you see if I go to modules
see these are all the standard modules
that you that are being provided by task
under t-box automation tool
example basic Windows operation
what kind of Bin Windows operations if
you want to send Keys you can send keys
or if you want to perform Windows
operation you can perform Windows
operation right if you want to scroll
window then you can scroll the window
and then file operations if you want to
compare the file you can use this module
so basically all these modules are
already built you need not to create a
separate script or you need not to build
a script
to basically use these operations right
file comparison they already provided to
you so you need not to build a script to
compare the file right and let's assume
t-box engine
let's say HTML under HTML see one simple
example
close browser open URL so you need not
to write any these are all the reusable
functions or modules that is provided by
Tasker so you need not to write
script for opening the URL you need not
to write script for row closing the
browser because I can reuse this n
number of times I can reuse this n
number of times in any test case
right that's an example and then if you
want to
let's go to some other
examples okay
open if you want to use any sap related
modules you can use sap related modules
if you want to use some Excel functions
like opening Excel book workbook
it's already available so you need not
to build a script for connecting the
Excel and then opening the Excel Book
closing the Excel book creating the
Excel worksheet right
deleting the Excel worksheet so you need
not to build all these things all these
things are available PDF comparing the
PDF you already have one module
available right so all these kind of
different kind of standard modules are
already available and you can use the
standard modules n number of times in
any
case that you would like to automate
okay it's really helpful it saves a lot
of time in automating any kind of
application
okay hope you all understand the concept
of standard modules
and also what is model based testing in
Tosca
okay if you have any queries you can
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your queries
thank you
foreign
[Music]